Contact

+55 (11) 98428-1366 (Mobile) felipe.miyazato@alumni.usp. br

www.linkedin.com/in/felipe-gomesmiyazato (LinkedIn) felipe-gomes-miyazato.github.io/ (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Statistical Analysis
Data Analytics
Data Engineering

Languages

English (Professional Working)
Spanish (Native or Bilingual)
Catalan (Native or Bilingual)
Portuguese (Native or Bilingual)

Felipe Gomes Miyazato

Physicist, data analyst and engineer

São Paulo, São Paulo, Brazil

Summary

I am a physicist graduated from IFUSP. I have been working for 6 years mainly with data analysis and engineering. Currently, I am directing my education towards working with data science. I am interested in research on machine learning applications.

Experience

Ali Crédito Data specialist

January 2022 - August 2023 (1 year 8 months)

São Paulo, Brazil

- Data analysis and BI with dashboards and iPython notebooks
- Data mining and web scraping for databases and CRM enrichment
- Design, development and management of integrations, data pipelines, process automations, ETLs, databases, calculation engines for financial products and CRM with Python and SQL in AWS
- Technical leadership with team and project management, code review
- Operational support and monitoring

GV2C Consulting & Solutions

Data Engineer

October 2020 - December 2021 (1 year 3 months)

- Automation and process optimization consulting for accounting reports
- Development of Python ETLs with cookiecutter
- Project planning and management

Freelance

Data Miner

July 2020 - August 2020 (2 months)

- Data mining and database consolidation scientific research purposes
- Project management
- Web-scraping with Scrapy and REST API. Parallel data processing with Dask

Predicta

Data Scientist

January 2020 - March 2020 (3 months)

- Development of Python ETLs in GCP environment (Big Query, Cloud Functions, and blob storages)
- Development of data integrations with Google digital marketing platforms

TEVEC Inteligência Artificial

Data scientist

July 2018 - November 2019 (1 year 5 months)

- Development and analysis of ML models with scikit-learn
- Modeling and analysis of time series for retail sales volume forecasts and supply chain optimization

Media Portal Soluções Software developer January 2017 - March 2017 (3 months) São Paulo, São Paulo, Brasil

- Projeto de integração de serviços de redes sociais com serviços AI para implementação de sistema de ranqueamento de conteúdo

Education

IFUSP

Bachelor's degree, Physics · (March 2014 - June 2020)

Universidade de São Paulo

Bachelor's degree, Molecular Sciences · (July 2014)